kbb.com 2013-09-28

# Privacy Policy - Kelley Blue Book

Last Updated: 9/5/2013

### What This Privacy Policy Covers

Thank you for visiting Kelley Blue Book Co., Inc.'s ("Kelley") kbb.com ("Kelley Site"). This policy applies to the kbb.com website and all related sites, applications, services and tools including mobile sites and applications where this policy is referenced, regardless of how you access or use them, including mobile devices.

Your privacy is important to us, and this policy will explain how we collect and use information that personally identifies you ("personal information") as well as non-personal information about your interaction with the Kelley Site. 

Third-party providers involved in the operation of the website (including, but not limited to, vendors of products and services and providers of widgets, tools, and applications) featured on or linked to by our website may also collect information about you. Their collection and use of this information will be subject to their privacy policies.

### The Information We Collect

You can interact with the Kelley Site in various ways, including, to obtain Kelley Blue Book® Values and pricing information, list a car for sale, research vehicles, read articles and reviews, subscribe to MyKBB and register to use the any community forums, answer surveys, and request more information about a vehicle of interest. We may collect information from you in connection with your interaction with the Kelley Site. 

Our web server (and/or any web server operated by our service provider(s) on our behalf) may collect and may store limited information about your device configuration when you visit the Kelley Site including the type of browser software you use, the operating system you are running, the resolution of your device’s screen, the make and model of your handset the website that referred you, the date and time you access the Kelley Site and your IP address. Your IP address is a numerical address that is used by devices connected to the Internet to identify your device so that data (such as the web pages you want to view) can be transmitted to you. We also use IP address information for systems administration (including fraud detection and prevention) and troubleshooting purposes. We may also collect information about the website you were visiting before you came to our website and the website you visit after you leave our website. 

We may collect, or have a third party collect on our behalf, data on how visitors use and navigate through the Websites, such as the number of users who visit various pages within the Websites, what they click on, whether they scroll up or down on particular pages, fill out forms, etc. 

We collect personal information from you, such as your name, address, phone number, and/or e-mail address when you provide it to us in connection with a service on the Kelley Site, such as when you request a Free Dealer Price Quote, list a car for sale, answer survey questions, and register to use the community forums and/or a MyKBB account. We may also receive personal information from you when you provide it indirectly, for example when you respond to a research survey with a marketing research supplier or provide personal information with comments when you Contact Us. Once you provide Kelley with personal information, you are not anonymous to us. 

When you list a car for sale, we ask for information on the car and on how you can be contacted by potential buyers (including information like your phone number and email address). We also ask for your credit card number and the expiration date on your card. We use this information to create your ad and to process your payment (please see the section on "Use and Disclosure of Information" below for more information about how we use and secure credit card information). We may also use information you submit to us in connection with your purchase of that listing, including your name and location, on third-party sites and mobile applications where we distribute or promote your listing. 

**Social Networks** When you use one of the social network sharing tools available on our website, we and the social network operating the tool may collect information about you based on such use. The social network’s use of that information will be subject to its own privacy policy, which may be different from this Privacy Statement. 

**Content You Post to our Website** If you choose to post content to any of the interactive areas of our website, such as discussion forums, comments fields and social media areas, please keep in mind that the information you post can be seen, collected and used by anyone who has access to those areas. You may also have the opportunity from time to time to respond to questions that we display to users of the website. If you choose to respond, your response may be published on an area of the website accessible to other users or the public. We are not responsible for any third-party use of such information. 

With your permission (e.g., by agreeing to let us use your current location when you first log in to our applications), our mobile site and/or applications may use precise, real-time geo-location technology to collect information about the exact location of your mobile device. We may also request your zip code. We may use either the zip code or real-time geo-location information to provide you with the content you request, such as search results of dealerships that are closest to you, or products or services we believe would be of interest to you. You can opt out of precise, real-time location-based information collection by visiting the "Settings" page of the application or by changing the location services settings on your device. 

### How We Use the Information

Kelley uses the information you provide for the following general purposes: to fulfill your requests for products and services, follow-up surveys, to contact you, to customize the content and advertising you see, to improve our services, to enforce the terms of use of the Kelley Site, and otherwise for the purposes for which you provided the information.

Kelley uses aggregate and non-personal information to conduct research and analysis and to create reports that we may provide to others, such as our business partners and customers. We may also use the non-personally identifiable information that we collect to improve the overall design and user experience of the Kelley Site, analyze trends, and administer the site.

In some cases, to provide you with a customized experience and to enhance our services, we (or third party service providers acting on our behalf) may combine information (including personally identifying information) that we collect through our website with information about you and/or your computer from other sources, including offline interactions with us, public databases, and third parties. 

Kelley may use the information it collects in order to display the targeted ads about goods and services of interest to you and others ("interest-based advertising"). Kelley may display interest-based advertising based on non-personal information such as your activity on the Kelley Site or other websites, or based on personal information you have provided; but, Kelley does not provide your personal information to the advertiser. For more information on our interest-based advertising practices, click here.

### Information Sharing and Disclosure

We may release or use information about our visitors when release is appropriate to comply with laws; to respond to legal process or to a valid law enforcement request; to enforce our Visitor Agreement; or to protect the rights, property or safety of visitors to our website, our customers, the public or Kelley. As our business grows, we may buy or sell various assets. In the unlikely event that Kelley, one of its business units, or substantially all of its assets is acquired by another company, information on our visitors would be among the transferred assets.

Kelley does not rent, sell, or share your personal information with other people or nonaffiliated companies except to provide products or services you've requested, when we have your permission, or under the following circumstances:

When you elect to receive information from Kelley, automobile manufacturers and local dealers and/or from Kelley's valued providers (finance, insurance, etc.), Kelley will use and/or share your personal information only as you have elected.

When you request a Free Dealer Price Quote, more information about a particular vehicle, or to be contacted by a dealer regarding a new or used vehicle, your personal information (including your contact information) may be forwarded by Kelley directly to the dealer or may be provided by Kelley to an automobile manufacturer or a trusted business partner that will forward your personal information to the dealer. Your personal information may also be forwarded by Kelley, the dealer, the automobile manufacturer or a trusted business partner to a trusted business partner or service provider, for the purpose of verifying your personal information, reviewing buyer purchase activity and reporting aggregate vehicle transaction data (excluding your personal information) to Kelley, the dealer, the automobile manufacturer, and/or a trusted business partner.

Please be aware that when you provide personal information to Kelley and authorize Kelley to share that information with a third party, your personal information becomes the property of Kelley and/or the third party. Kelley and/or the third party may use your personal information to process your request and provide valuable services. Keep in mind that once Kelley shares your personal information with a dealer or other third party as you have requested, Kelley may no longer have control over the use of the information by those third parties.

Kelley may share non-personal information about your interaction with the Kelley Site and other Web sites in order to provide interest-based ads to you and others on the Kelley Site or on other websites. Kelley and its trusted partners and third-party advertising companies may note some of the pages you visit through the use of pixel tags. Kelley and third-party advertising companies (which may include network advertisers) may use information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. For more information on our interest-based advertising practices, click here.

When we use other companies to help us operate our website or improve the services we offer to you, we may provide them with information about our visitors that is necessary for them to perform their services. We require that these companies commit to use the information only to perform the services that we request.

If you choose to unsubscribe in response to an email message that we send on behalf of an advertiser, we will share your email address and opt-out instructions with the advertiser. Similarly, if we ask a third-party company to send its customers email offers on our behalf, we will share with that company (or its agent) a list of email addresses collected from website visitors who have opted out of our email program. 

Although we take appropriate measures to protect against unauthorized disclosures of information, we cannot assure you that the information we collect will never be disclosed in a manner that is inconsistent with this privacy policy.

We may share this information with our affiliates, including AutoTrader Group, Inc. and any of their subsidiaries, so that we and they may provide you with information, products, and services that we believe may be of interest to you.

**If you do not want your information to be used for marketing by Kelley and/or a third party, do not provide the information, "opt in" or otherwise agree to such use, or "opt out," as appropriate.**

### Cookies

Kelley may set and access Kelley cookies on your computer. A cookie is a small text file that is placed on your hard drive by a Web page server. Cookies are uniquely assigned to you, and are encoded so they can only be read by a Web server in the domain that issued the cookie to you. One of the primary purposes of cookies is to provide a convenience feature to save you time. For example, if you personalize a Web page, or navigate within a site, a cookie helps the site to recall your specific information (such as your ZIP Code) on subsequent visits. This simplifies the process of delivering relevant content, eases site navigation, and so on. When you return to the Web site, the information you previously provided can be retrieved, so you can easily use the site's features that you customized.

Kelley lets other companies, including business partners and companies that show advertisements on some of our pages, set and access their cookies on your computer. Other companies' use of their cookies is subject to their own privacy policies.

You have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most Web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. If you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to fully experience the interactive features of this or other Web sites you visit.

### Web Beacons

Kelley uses Web beacons (also known as clear gif technology, pixels, or action tags) to access Kelley cookies inside and outside our Web site and to collect data and allow other companies to collect data. Web beacons may be used to assist in delivering cookies on our site. This technology is a tool we may also use to compile aggregated statistics about the Kelley Site usage, such as how many visitors clicked on key elements (such as links or graphics) on a page. We may share aggregated site statistics with other companies, and we may allow other companies to place their pixels and/or set cookies on our site.

Cookies, beacons, information collected about your computer or device, and other data collection technologies ("Data Technologies") may be used individually or in combination in order to provide and/or administer our services, to help us understand user behavior, to monitor website performance, optimize ads and measure advertising performance. 

### Collection of Information by Third-Party Sites and Providers

Kelley has relationships with certain third-party advertising networks, Advertisers, and advertising services ("Advertising Services") that collect data, target and serve some of the advertisements, promotions, or other marketing messages you see on our website and other websites and mobile applications, including the websites owned and/or operated by our affiliates. 

Such Advertising Services may, through processes that we do not control, use Data Technologies from third party companies to collect data from your activities on these websites, on other websites owned and/or operated by our affiliates, or with other websites. These technologies may be used to track user behavior, how our products and services are offered, conduct consumer research and possibly to serve you relevant ads and content. These companies may also obtain information, including personally identifiable information, from services you use from other companies, including without limitation, other websites, mobile website or applications, and combine the information they obtain through these Data Technologies with information obtained through our products and services. Their collection and use of this data is subject to their own privacy policies. To learn more and to opt out of such data collection, you should visit [http://www.evidon.com](http://www.evidon.com/) to opt out of these services.

If you click on a third-party link, including a social media graphic link on the Kelley Site, you will be taken to the third party's Web site, and your information will be subject to the third party's privacy policy. Likewise, whenever you opt in to receive future communications from a third party, your information will be subject to the third party's privacy policy. You should always review the privacy policy of any party that collects your information to determine how that entity will handle your information, as we have no control over information that is submitted to, or collected by, these third parties.

Kelley Site content is also integrated into other Web sites. These Web sites may collect personal information from their visitors that may or may not be used in conjunction with the Kelley Site content. Prior to supplying any personal information to any third party company that links to the Kelley Site, please read and understand their privacy policy.

Advertisements served by our website advertising technology vendor appear on pages throughout the Kelley Site. Some advertisements may request personal information directly from you or take you to Web sites that may request your personal information. Kelley has no control over these advertisers' privacy policies, so please examine the privacy policy of any company advertising on the Kelley Web site prior to submitting any personal information in connection with the advertisement.

Kelley utilizes reputable third party service providers to track and analyze non-personally identifiable aggregate usage information, such as tracking, data collection, reporting, ad response measurement, and site analytics, to assist us in improving the quality of the Kelley Site. These third parties may view, edit or set their own cookies or data collection code. The use of these technologies by these third parties is subject to their own privacy policies and is not covered by this privacy statement.

### Interest-Based Ads

At kbb.com, we want to provide you with ads that are relevant to you, and we try to display ads that we think you will find interesting and meaningful. Using interest-based advertising, we are able to provide relevant ads that are aimed at your specific interests.

Based on your activity on Kelley Site or on other websites, we may infer your interest in a particular product or service and display an ad that relates to those interests. For example, if you've been viewing pages related to SUVs on kbb.com, you are more likely to see ads about certain SUVs as you browse our website.

We offer you choices with regard to interest-based advertising. Kbb.com is a participant in the online industry's self regulatory program administered by the Digital Advertising Alliance (the "DAA") and has agreed to adhere to the DAA's principles applicable to interest-based ads. Please visit [http://www.aboutads.info](http://www.aboutads.info/) for more information about the DAA, the self regulatory principles and choices you can make regarding interest-based advertising. You may find more information about additional choices you may make through the Network Advertising Initiative ("NAI") at the [NAI site](http://www.networkadvertising.org/).

To learn more about interest-based advertising and the choices available to you, please visit our interest-based advertising page.

### Security

Kelley takes commercially reasonable steps to ensure information we gather on our website is stored in a secure manner. Any credit card information you may provide us is secured for transmission over the Internet using industry-standard Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) encryption. While we work hard to protect your privacy, no physical or electronic security system is impenetrable, or invulnerable to attack, including your own, and the ones used to transmit your data to us. We cannot and do not guarantee that our systems, or your information, will be secure.

### International Visitors

This website is intended for use by visitors within the United States. If you reside outside the United States, please be aware that (i) our databases are stored on servers and storage devices located in the United States, (ii) your information (including personal data) may be transferred to the United States for processing and storage, and (iii) the United States, and the localities within the United States where our databases are located, may not guarantee the same level of protection for personal data as the locality or country in which you reside. By using our website, you expressly agree to our collection, use, disclosure, and transfer of your information (including personal data) for the purposes identified herein, and you consent to the transfer of such information outside of your country.

### Protection of Children's Personal Information

Our website is not directed at or intended for children under 13 and we will not knowingly allow anyone under 13 to provide us any personally identifying information; if you are under 13, please do not provide any information about yourself on this website.

### Changes to this privacy policy

Kelley may occasionally update this privacy policy. When we do, we will also revise the "last updated" date at the top of the privacy policy. We encourage you to periodically review this privacy policy to stay informed about how we are helping to protect the personal information we collect. Your continued use of the service constitutes your agreement to this privacy policy and any updates.

### Your California Privacy Rights

For information on Your California Privacy Rights, see California Notice of Information-Sharing Disclosure.

### How to Contact Us

If you have any questions or concerns about this privacy policy or its implementation you may contact us at [privacy@kbb.com](mailto:privacy@kbb.com).
